rose-hulman.edu 2018-08-31

# Privacy Statement | Rose-Hulman

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to the privacy of our visitors, and to describe the information-gathering and dissemination practices for the website.

This website may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process involving the website.

All information provided to Rose-Hulman electronically is kept confidential and will not be applied in ways to which visitors have not consented. Rose-Hulman will not sell or disclose any information that identifies a visitor to a third party without that visitor’s consent.

Rose-Hulman does collect information about the use of its site through the application of “cookies.” This information allows for site customization, and to statistically monitor how many people are using the site and the types of behaviors the end visitors exhibit once on the site.

Encryption is used for the transfer of data. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. As a result, while Rose-Hulman strives to protect personal information, the institute cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information transmitted to or from its web sites.

**Copyright­­**

The purpose of the Rose-Human website is to provide information and services related to the institute’s programs and services. All materials are provided solely for personal, institutional, or non-commercial use.

All content on the Rose-Hulman website is copyrighted. Material may not be broadcast, circulated, disseminated, distributed, downloaded, modified, published, reproduced, retransmitted, reused, sold, or otherwise used except as expressly stated either in such materials or in this notice without the express written permission of Rose-Hulman. For permission to reproduce copyrighted materials, contact the [Office of Communications and Marketing](http://www.rose-hulman.edu/about-us/community-and-public-services/communications-and-marketing.html).

**Links to Other Sites**

This site contains links to other sites. This site is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

**Updates to This Privacy Statement**

Rose-Hulman has the right to modify this statement at any time. If you have questions about this statement, please check this statement periodically or contact the site’s [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@rose-hulman.edu).

**Collecting Personal Information**

Rose-Hulman collects information from you when you register for an event through its site, fill out a form or enter information on the site.

**Using personal information**

Rose-Hulman may use the information it collects to easily process transactions, send periodic emails for which the visitor expressly requested, or to process other transactions at the request of the visitor.

**Protecting personal information**

The Rose-Hulman website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make visiting the site as safe as possible. The website utilizes a variety of online security efforts to protect visitor personal information. Personal and sensitive information is stored behind secured networks and only accessible to a limited number of persons who have special access permissions to such systems and are required to keep such information confidential. The institute will comply with all applicable legislative, regulatory, and contractual requirements concerning collected protected information.

**Cookies**

Visitors can choose through browser settings to have their computer warn them each time a cookie is being sent, or can choose to turn off all cookies.

If cookies are disabled, some features could be disabled that make the site experience more efficient and some services on the site may not function properly.

**Third-Party Disclosure**

Rose-Hulman does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

**Third party behavioral tracking**

Third-party vendors, such as Google and Facebook, may use cookies, web beacons or other technologies to serve ads, provide analytics, or deliver content on other websites based on visits to this site. These third parties may automatically collect information about visits to this and other websites, including the IP address, browser information and other metrics using cookies and other technologies. The use of the above services does not create personally identifiable data to Rose-Hulman nor any other party. While Rose-Hulman may offer visitors web-based forms to complete, which could collect identifying information, the institute does not actively share this information. This statement does not apply to, and Rose-Hulman is not responsible for, cookies or other technologies used by third parties. We encourage visitors to review the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technologies. To manage settings for the Google advertising cookies and to opt-out of certain features, visit their [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous). To opt out of cookies or obtain more information about Google’s practices, [visit Google Analytics available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). Learn more about all digital opt-out options at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> and <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>.

**Fair Information Practices**

This site follows fair information practices.

**﻿Homework Hotline**

Information collected for purposes of the Homework Hotline is not shared with third parties. Information is collected directly from the student seeking assistance from the Hotline. Information collected may include a student’s first name, email address, grade, school, and state. The information collected is used to provide assistance to the student with his or her homework-related questions. Rose-Hulman may also use a student’s information to inform the student of services offered by the Hotline.

**Non-Discrimination Statement**

Please refer to the Rose-Hulman [Policy on Equal Opportunity, Harassment and Nondiscrimination](http://www.rose-hulman.edu/about-us/human-resources/title-ix.html).

**CAN SPAM Act**

This site will not use false, misleading subjects or email addresses; will identify advertising messages as such; will include the physical address of the institute on the website; will monitor third-party email services for compliance, if used; will honor opt-out and unsubscribe requests in a timely manner; and will provide an unsubscribe link in the bottom of emails.

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this site, please contact the site’s [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@rose-hulman.edu).
